<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>[ ) Between Two Ranges ( ]</title><link href="http://rlvoyer.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://rlvoyer.github.io/feeds/misc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://rlvoyer.github.io/</id><updated>2015-12-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>Open Data and Search Relevance</title><link href="http://rlvoyer.github.io/open-data-and-search-relevance.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-12-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Robert Voyer</name></author><id>tag:rlvoyer.github.io,2015-12-06:open-data-and-search-relevance.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href="http://www.socrata.com"&gt;Socrata&lt;/a&gt;, we have built a data platform that enables
government agencies to be more transparent than ever before. One of the
interesting byproducts of the continued adoption of our platform is a constantly
evolving network of open data publishers. When you have all of the world's open
data within the same platform, interesting opportunities for cross-dataset
insights and connectivity become possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My team has been busy building out some of the software that will allow us to
begin to surface this network to our users. Our first product offering along
these lines is the search engine powering the
&lt;a href="http://www.opendatanetwork.com"&gt;Open Data Network&lt;/a&gt;. As it happens, it is also
the same system that backs our version 2 catalog search interface, which our
customers interact with regularly when they visit their Socrata site's browse
endpoint (eg.  &lt;a href="http://data.seattle.gov/browse"&gt;data.seattle.gov/browse&lt;/a&gt;) to
update, analyze, and visualize their data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have spent some time recently trying to improve this core piece of technology
both in terms of performance as well as accuracy and relevance. In this blog
post, I will discuss how we use crowdsourcing to collect relevance judgments to
measure the quality of the search results in our catalog search engine. The
high-level steps are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sample a set of queries from query logs to serve as
   &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/rlvoyer/c5dc896a39ab69288024"&gt;a measurement set&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;given a particular version of the search engine, collect results for each
   query in the measurement set&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;assign a relevance judgment to each (query, result) pair&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;compute relevance metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building an amazing search experience isn't easy. Google has set the standard;
as users, we expect our search results instantaneously, and we expect them to be
highly relevant. How does Google do it so well? There has been
&lt;a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2015-10-26/google-turning-its-lucrative-web-search-over-to-ai-machines"&gt;some recent discussion&lt;/a&gt;
about Google's use of a new AI system as an additional signal in their search
result ranking model. It has been standard practice in the industry for some
time to have a machine learned ranking model -- often an
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_neural_network"&gt;artificial neural network&lt;/a&gt;
-- that incorporates a variety of signals. But rather than focus on the
internals of an open dataset search engine, I want to talk about how to measure
relevance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have long been a fan of the following quote: "you cannot improve what you
cannot measure". The first step in improving any search engine is being able to
compute a metric that captures the quality of results.
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Precision_and_recall"&gt;Precision and recall&lt;/a&gt; are
often thought of as the de facto metrics for Information Retrieval systems. But
there are a couple of notable shortcomings of precision and recall (and the
closely related
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/F1_score"&gt;F-measure&lt;/a&gt;, which combines precision
and recall into a single measure). Firstly, recall is generally difficult to
measure within the context of search engine because it requires knowing and
judging the relevance of all possible results for a particular query. In some
cases, the cardinality of that result set could be on the order of hundreds of
thousands. Additionally, neither precision, recall, nor F-measure take into
account the ordering of results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As users, we expect the most relevant results to be at the top of the search
engine results page (SERP). We rarely even look beyond the first page. According
to &lt;a href="https://moz.com/blog/google-organic-click-through-rates-in-2014"&gt;this study&lt;/a&gt;
by the folks at &lt;a href="https://moz.com/"&gt;Moz&lt;/a&gt;, about 71% of Google searches result in
a click on the first page and the first 5 results account for 68% of all
clicks. In Socrata’s catalog search engine, only 6% of users click past the
first page. Normalized discounted cumulative gain (NDCG) has seen widespread
adoption as a core metric in the search industry precisely because it accounts
for our expectation as users that the best results be at the top of the SERP
(and that results further down the list contribute less to our perception of
quality).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how do we compute NDCG? Cumulative gain is a measure we apply to an
individual query based on the results in our results list (usually capped at
position 5 or 10). To compute it, we must assign a relevance score to each
result in our results list, and then we simply sum relevance scores at each
position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="math"&gt;$$ CG_p = \sum_{i=1}^n rel_i $$&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; where &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="math"&gt;$$ rel_i = \{0, 1, 2, 3\} $$&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes NDCG effective is its discount term. Discounted cumulative gain is a
simple variation on the CG function defined above:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="math"&gt;$$ DCG_p = rel_1 + \sum_{i=2}^n {rel_i \over D(i)} $$&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; where &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="math"&gt;$$ D(i) = log_2(i + 1) $$&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea here is that we have a discount function in the denominator that is a
monotonically increasing function of position. Thus, the denominator increases
as we go further down the results list, meaning that each result contributes
less to the overall sum of scores. (Strictly speaking, we use the second
variant described on the
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discounted_cumulative_gain"&gt;Wikipedia page for NDCG&lt;/a&gt;
.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the score is "normalized" (the "N" in "NDCG"). DCG is a measure that we
compute for each query, but not all queries are created equal. For some queries,
a search engine may have 10 or more highly relevant results. For other queries,
there may be far fewer or none at all. In order to be able to compare across
queries (or average across them to capture the search engine's performance across
an entire query set), we need them all to be on the same scale. To do this, we
normalize the DCG of each query by the DCG of the best possible ordering of the
same results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="math"&gt;$$ NDCG_p = {DCG_p \over IDCG_p} $$&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; where &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="math"&gt;$$ IDCG_p $$&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; is the DCG applied to the ideal
set of results for a given query.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In practice, we collect more and more judgments for a particular query-result
pair over time as we compare more and more variants of our system. When we go to
normalize our DCG score, we take as ideals the best possible ordering of the
best results from the history of all judged query-result pairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's consider an example. We have a query "crime incidents" and the top 5
results are judged to be "perfect", "irrelevant", "relevant", "loosely
relevant", and "loosely relevant" respectively (represented on our numeric scale
as 3, 0, 2, 1, 1). A corresponding ideal ordering would be 3, 2, 1, 1, 0. And we
could compute NDCG like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;math&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;dcg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;judgments&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class="c"&gt;# the +2 in the discount term because of 0-based indexing&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;sum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;([&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;enumerate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;judgments&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)])&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;ndcg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;judgments&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;ideal_dcg&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;dcg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;sorted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;judgments&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;reverse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="bp"&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;dcg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;judgments&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;ideal_dcg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;ideal_dcg&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mf"&gt;0.0&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;ndcg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;([&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;])&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="mf"&gt;0.927779663887&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In order to attach a metric to our search engine's performance, we need
relevance judgments for each query-result pair. How do we collect these
measurements? Well, the most obvious way is to hire an army of data annotators
and to have them assign a judgment to each query-result pair. As it turns out,
this is one of the tasks that workers in
&lt;a href="http://searchengineland.com/bing-search-quality-rating-guidelines-130592"&gt;Microsoft's Human Relevance System&lt;/a&gt;
and
&lt;a href="http://marketingland.com/an-inside-look-at-what-googles-search-quality-raters-do-3969"&gt;Google's Quality Rater program&lt;/a&gt;
are asked to do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of Microsoft and Google, the people hired to make these relevance
judgments are trained. Certainly, part of the motivation for this is that it
allows Google and Microsoft to craft a much more nuanced task. This allows them
to incorporate more than just search term relevance into their judgments
(freshness, authority, etc.). In contrast, there are a few companies that offer
crowdsourcing services like
&lt;a href="https://www.mturk.com/mturk/welcome"&gt;Amazon Mechanical Turk&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="http://www.crowdflower.com/"&gt;CrowdFlower&lt;/a&gt; with dynamic workforces consisting of
untrained workers, which is typically much more cost effective than training and
managing your own team of annotators. (I was happy to discover local
new-kids-on-the-block &lt;a href="https://zcrowd.com/"&gt;ZCrowd&lt;/a&gt; who are focusing on dynamic
skilled workforces.) One key observation here is that the level of training
required is very much task-dependent. For Socrata, the task of assigning
relevance judgments as we have framed it, while somewhat subjective and
occasionally nuanced, is relatively straightforward, and thus, a workforce of
untrained workers is sufficient (for now). We track the quality of the
annotations that we collect by comparing crowdsourced judgments on a sample of
data to corresponding judgments assigned by in-house experts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few different dimensions to consider when designing our relevance
task. The first is the arity of the task. Do you present the annotator with a
single result (pointwise), a pair of results (pairwise), or a list of results
(listwise)? The next dimension to think about is the type of judgment. Should
you collect binary relevance labels, scalar relevance judgments, or should you
simply ask the assessor to provide an ordering between results in a list? There
are pros and cons to each of these approaches, which I've enumerated in the
table below. Ultimately, we have adopted the pointwise approach, with absolute,
scalar judgments, which has a few advantages. The first is its simplicity. As a
simpler task, it can be completed more quickly and more reliably by
annotators. But also, it's the most cost effective approach because it requires
the fewest judgments. A judgment made about a query-result pair in isolation is
absolute and reusable; once a particular QRP has been judged, it never has to be
judged again. Given the task's inherent subjectivity, we opted for scalar
judgments (rather than binary judgments) since they allow us to to capture as
much information as possible at a reasonable cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;table border="1"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th colspan="2"&gt;Listwise&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pros&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cons&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;directly reflects the underlying process being modeled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;includes context (of surrounding results)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;complex annotation task&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;judgments are not reusable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th colspan="2"&gt;Pairwise&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pros&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cons&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple annotation task&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reusable judgments (assuming &lt;a href="#transitivity"&gt;transitivity&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;requires n&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; (worst-case) judgments [&lt;a href="#transitivity"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th colspan="2"&gt;Pointwise&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pros&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cons&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple annotation task&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reusable "absolute" judgments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cost effective given simplicity and reusability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple implementation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;many simplifying assumptions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name="transitivity"&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href="http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/um/people/pauben/papers/HereOrThere-ECIR-2008.pdf"&gt;Carterette et al&lt;/a&gt;
set out to show that pairwise judgments are the simplest for assessors. They show
that relevance judgments typically obey transitivity, which means that the full
set of n&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; pairwise judgments is not actually required. For our part,
we have trouble justifying the complexity involved in building such a system
given the marginal gain in task simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our typical task looks as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Task Screenshot" src="http://rlvoyer.github.io/images/unit.pedestrian_counts.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the platform (presently, we're using CrowdFlower), we can collect
job output programmatically via API as JSON or from a GUI as a CSV. We persist
query sets and judgments in a Postgres database with an eye towards
reproducibility, while also ensuring that we never unintentionally re-submit
previously judged pairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One neat feature of CrowdFlower is its quality control mechanism. We, the task
designers, are prompted to enter "gold" data, which is used to a) avoid
collecting bad data from scammers, and b) help instruct workers, and c) weight
the judgments provided by workers according to their trustworthiness. Getting
multiple judgments for each QRP allows us to average out the results, thus
getting a more reliable signal than had each QRP been judged only once. Looking
at the variance of the judgments provided by our workers, we can identify
particularly difficult and nuanced pairs, which may serve as valuable test data
for its instructional value. Additionally, including these high-variance QRPs as
test data helps us to better quantify the quality of work that we're getting
from each annotator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, we have collected judgments for about 6000 query-result
pairs. This is just a start, but it's enough for us to start doing some
interesting things. Most importantly, it has allowed us to directly compare our
catalog search systems -- old vs. new -- in terms of relevance. And the results
are encouraging; in addition to the obvious increase in performance, and the
improvements to the UI, the new system produces more relevant results than the
old. We have created &lt;a href="http://www.github.com/socrata/arcs"&gt;a Python package&lt;/a&gt; to
support this process that is publicly available on Github. Any feedback is
much appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crowdsourced relevance judgments only tell part of the story; they are a proxy
for how real users perceive the quality of our search results. In future posts,
I will write in more detail about collecting usage data and computing online
metrics such as
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Click-through_rate"&gt;Click-Through Rate&lt;/a&gt;, and
subsequently using click data to train a machine learned ranking model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://moz.com/blog/google-organic-click-through-rates-in-2014"&gt;"Google Organic Click-through Rates in 2014", Philip Petrescu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://hughewilliams.com/2014/10/11/measuring-search-relevance/"&gt;"Measuring Search Relevance", Hugh Williams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://searchengineland.com/bing-search-quality-rating-guidelines-130592"&gt;"Yes, Bing Has Human Search Quality Raters &amp;amp; Here’s How They Judge Web Pages", Matt McGee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/people/tyliu/listnet.pdf"&gt;Learning to rank: from pairwise approach to listwise approach, Cao, Qin, Liu et al.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/um/people/pauben/papers/HereOrThere-ECIR-2008.pdf"&gt;Here or There: Preference Judgments for Relevance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;if (!document.getElementById('mathjaxscript_pelican_#%@#$@#')) {
    var align = "center",
        indent = "0em",
        linebreak = "false";

    if (false) {
        align = (screen.width &lt; 768) ? "left" : align;
        indent = (screen.width &lt; 768) ? "0em" : indent;
        linebreak = (screen.width &lt; 768) ? 'true' : linebreak;
    }

    var mathjaxscript = document.createElement('script');
    var location_protocol = (false) ? 'https' : document.location.protocol;
    if (location_protocol !== 'http' &amp;&amp; location_protocol !== 'https') location_protocol = 'https:';
    mathjaxscript.id = 'mathjaxscript_pelican_#%@#$@#';
    mathjaxscript.type = 'text/javascript';
    mathjaxscript.src = location_protocol + '//cdn.mathjax.org/mathjax/latest/MathJax.js?config=TeX-AMS-MML_HTMLorMML';
    mathjaxscript[(window.opera ? "innerHTML" : "text")] =
        "MathJax.Hub.Config({" +
        "    config: ['MMLorHTML.js']," +
        "    TeX: { extensions: ['AMSmath.js','AMSsymbols.js','noErrors.js','noUndefined.js'], equationNumbers: { autoNumber: 'AMS' } }," +
        "    jax: ['input/TeX','input/MathML','output/HTML-CSS']," +
        "    extensions: ['tex2jax.js','mml2jax.js','MathMenu.js','MathZoom.js']," +
        "    displayAlign: '"+ align +"'," +
        "    displayIndent: '"+ indent +"'," +
        "    showMathMenu: true," +
        "    messageStyle: 'normal'," +
        "    tex2jax: { " +
        "        inlineMath: [ ['\\\\(','\\\\)'] ], " +
        "        displayMath: [ ['$$','$$'] ]," +
        "        processEscapes: true," +
        "        preview: 'TeX'," +
        "    }, " +
        "    'HTML-CSS': { " +
        "        styles: { '.MathJax_Display, .MathJax .mo, .MathJax .mi, .MathJax .mn': {color: 'inherit ! important'} }," +
        "        linebreaks: { automatic: "+ linebreak +", width: '90% container' }," +
        "    }, " +
        "}); " +
        "if ('default' !== 'default') {" +
            "MathJax.Hub.Register.StartupHook('HTML-CSS Jax Ready',function () {" +
                "var VARIANT = MathJax.OutputJax['HTML-CSS'].FONTDATA.VARIANT;" +
                "VARIANT['normal'].fonts.unshift('MathJax_default');" +
                "VARIANT['bold'].fonts.unshift('MathJax_default-bold');" +
                "VARIANT['italic'].fonts.unshift('MathJax_default-italic');" +
                "VARIANT['-tex-mathit'].fonts.unshift('MathJax_default-italic');" +
            "});" +
            "MathJax.Hub.Register.StartupHook('SVG Jax Ready',function () {" +
                "var VARIANT = MathJax.OutputJax.SVG.FONTDATA.VARIANT;" +
                "VARIANT['normal'].fonts.unshift('MathJax_default');" +
                "VARIANT['bold'].fonts.unshift('MathJax_default-bold');" +
                "VARIANT['italic'].fonts.unshift('MathJax_default-italic');" +
                "VARIANT['-tex-mathit'].fonts.unshift('MathJax_default-italic');" +
            "});" +
        "}";
    (document.body || document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0]).appendChild(mathjaxscript);
}
&lt;/script&gt;</summary><category term="software engineering"></category><category term="information retrieval"></category><category term="search"></category><category term="open data"></category></entry></feed>